<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts on Knowledge Hub</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Knowledge Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Firewall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/firewall/</guid>
      <description>A firewall provides a means to protect machines from any unwanted traffic. It enables users/administrators to control incoming network traffic on host machines by defining a set of firewall rules. These rules are used to sort the incoming traffic and either block it or allow through.&#xA;firewalld firewalld is a firewall service daemon that provides a dynamic customizable host-based firewall. Being dynamic, it enables creating, changing, and deleting the rules without the necessity to restart the firewall daemon each time the rules are changed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/networking/</guid>
      <description>Warning net-tools utilities are obsoleted by iproute2&#xA;https://wiki.linuxfoundation.org/networking/iproute2 Legacy utility Replacement command Note ifconfig ip addr, ip link, ip -s Address and link configuration route ip route Routing tables arp ip neigh Neighbors iptunnel ip tunnel Tunnels nameif ifrename, ip link set name Rename network interfaces ipmaddr ip maddr Multicast netstat ip -s, ss, ip route Socket statistics ip address statistics with colors and human readable format ip -stats -color -human addr</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/linux/concepts/users/</guid>
      <description>How to create a non-login user? Create user with -M (caps) flag. Lock the account to prevent from login useradd -M subversion usermod -L subversion How to create a system user ? $ adduser --system -s usr/sbin/nologin subversion # The -r flag will create a system user - one which does not have a password, a home dir and is unable to login. # -s flag is for shell , /bin/nologin prevents to have a shell for this user.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
